FAUZIA NAUSHAD SHAIKH

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

2.7+ years of experience as a Full Stack Developer with a demonstrated history of working in the software industry. Skilled in Google Cloud Platform(Kubernetes), Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD), Apache Kafka, Jenkins, Git, Bitbucket, Grafana, Terraform. Having a firm hold on the Cloud technologies.

Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor of Technology focused in Computer Science and Engineering from Maulana Azad National Institute of Technology.



CONTACT



Surat, Gujarat



+91-8989518570



fauziashaikh2601@gmail.com



www.linkedin.com/in/FauziaNShaikh



https://github.com/FAUZIANSHAIKH

EDUCATION

National Institute of Technology, Bhopal

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering June 2015 - May 2019

GPA - 7.71

SKILLS























ighthouse



WORK EXPERIENCE

DEVOPS LEAD

LOWE'S CANADA ONLINE ORDER PROJECT | November 2021 - Present

Responsibilities:

- Structured the Infrastructure Architecture for Frontend and Backend for the project.
- Created Jenkins pipelines for Continuous Integration.
- Created Namespaces.
- Containerized applications using Docker.
- Continuous Delivery through Spinnaker
- SonarQube Integration

Skills Gained - CI/CD, Jenkins, Spinnaker, Google Cloud Platform, Docker, Kubernetes, Groovy, Git.

DEVOPS ENGINEER

LOWE'S CANADA DIGITAL PROJECT | August 2020 - November 2021

Responsibilities:

- Continuous Integration through Jenkins and Continuous Delivery through Spinnaker
- Creating Namespace
- Containersing applications using Docker
- Creating Load Balancers and Clusters
- SonarQube Integration, Lighthouse Integration, Webhook Integration and Veracode Integration
- Automated pipelines for deploying fixed assets
- k6 load test automation
- Setting up Grafana Dashboards
- Google Cloud Logging Performed all the Production Deployments
- Trained 5-6 new joinees in the DEVOPS team through knowledge transfer sessions.

Skills Gained - CI/CD, Jenkins, Spinnaker, Google Cloud Platform, Docker, Kubernetes, Groovy, Git.

CERTIFICATIONS

- 1. Google Cloud Associate Cloud Engineer
- 2. Learning Docker Linked In Learning
- 3. DevOps CI/CD for Beginners Udemy
- 4. GCP Fundamentals Core Infrastructure Owiklahs
- 5. Google Cloud Infrastructure Scaling and Automation Qwiklabs
- Google Cloud Infrastructure Foundation Owiklabs
- 7. Google Cloud Infrastructure Core Services Qwiklabs
- 8. Google Cloud Application Development Coursera

BACKEND DEVELOPER

Point Of Sale Project | September 2019 - August 2020

Responsibilities:

- Developed microservices in NodeJS.
- Stored the data in PostgreSQL.
- Created Kafka communication for the microservices.
- Implemented CI/CD by creating the build triggers for the services.
- Creating cloud endpoints for all the APIs of the microservices.
- This Project helped us gain clients like McDonalds, Lowe's and Falabella for the company.

Skills Gained - PostgreSQL, Kafka, Git, Google Cloud Platform, CI/CD using Build triggers in Google Cloud, Google Cloud Endpoints, Camunda Rule Engine, Docker, Kubernetes, Load Balancers. .

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Certificate of Merit AISSCE May 2015
 Received the Certificate of Merit in English for securing highest marks in Class XII (AISSCE) 2015
- 2. Won medals in 4x100m Relay Running Race, 100 m Running Race 1

INTERESTS & HOBBIES

- 1. Baking
- 2. Art Work
- 3. TV Shows
- 4. Dancing

PERSONAL PROJECTS

TERRAFORM PROJECT | May 2021 - June 2021

Worked on automating the creation, modification and deletion of compute engines, VPC networks, subnets through Jenkins and Git.

Skills Gained - Jenkins, Continuous Integration and Deployment, Git, Google Cloud, Compute Engine, Subnets, VPC

REACT APPLICATION | May 2021 - June 2021

Worked on creating a To-Do task tracker which adds and removes task using clicks using React and storing the data in the JSON server. Using most of the functionalities of React.

Skills Gained - React and JSON server

SPRING BOOT APPLICATION | Jun. 2020 to July 2020

Worked on a Java Spring Boot Application that inserts, deletes and modifies Employee Data using MySQL and enabled caching using Redis Cache.

Skills Gained - Java and MySQL.

Effective Book Issuing Using RFID | Jan. 2019 to Mar 2019

Build a Device for automating the Issuing of Book in Library using RFID tags and reducing the need of manual issuing and human work, sped up book borrowing, monitoring, book searching processes, enhanced customer service.

Skills Gained - Internet of Things

Frequent Subgraph Mining | Oct. 2018 to Dec 2018

Depth-first search-based mining algorithm, which I was employed for efficient mining of frequent subgraphs in an extensive graph database

Skills Gained - Data Mining and Algorithms